Guide to the Steichen Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- February 2014 Acquisition, 1896-2010; 25.67; (28 boxes)
  - Audiovisual Material
    - Mary Steichen Calderone oral history, 1986-1987; 30 audiocassettes (Box 26)
      - "personal perp. home", copy, 22.1, 1987 September 10; 1 (Box 26, Item barcode 39002099365703)
      - "personal perp. in late 50s", copy, 1987 September 10; 1 (Box 26, Item barcode 39002099365737)
      - "personal perp. 60s", copy, 24, 1987 September 14; 1 (Box 26, Item barcode 39002099365729)
    - "Edward J. Steichen: A Documentary by Claude Waringo", 1995; 1; 00:57:42 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365349)
      Box 27 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Edward Steichen Documentary, undated; 1 (Box 27)
      This is a duplicate copy. It has not been digitized.
    - "Echoes and Silences: Sandburg Documentary", undated; 1; 02:00:56; The video quality is poor. Ghosting, an image super-imposed on top of another image, occurs throughout the tape. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365356)
    - "Steichen: A Century in Photography", undated; 1; 01:00:19 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365364)
    - "The Dedication of Steichen Court", 1988; 1; 00:52:00 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365372)
    - Kate Steichen (1 of 4), 1983 March 23; 1; 00:45:57; The program ends abruptly. The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365380)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Kate Steichen (2 of 4), 1983 March 23; 1; 00:47:25; The program ends abruptly. Audio is sometimes inaudible or muffled. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365398)
      Interview for the Wilton Oral History project
    - Kate Steichen (3 of 4), 1983 March 23; 1; 00:47:56; The program ends abruptly. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365406)
    - Kate Steichen (4 of 4), 1983 March 23; 1; 00:37:17; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard on the tape. The right channel was recorded at a lower level for the first 23 minutes. The program ends abruptly. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365414)
    - Kate Steichen II, undated; 1; 00:47:13; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365422)
    - Carol's 80th Birthday (Dick Scheidker), 1979 July 15; 1; 01:02:26; The program is distorted at times. A high amount of hiss is on the tape. Audio sometimes sounds weak or hollow. The program ends abruptly. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365430)
    - The Don Cossack Chorus, 1949 / Bumpa's Lord's Prayer, undated; 1; 00:30:16; There is static on the tape. Clicks and pops can be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 27, Item barcode 39002099365448)
      Contents include: "The Lord's Prayer", "The Sailors", "On Saturday", "A Hazel Tree", "Holy God", "The Twelve Robbers", "The Indian Guest", "Blessed Art Thou, O Lord".
- 5 June 2014 Acquisition, 1904-2014; 10.83; (11 boxes)
  - Photographs of or by Edward Steichen, 1974; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Whitney Museum correspondence, 1996-2001 (Box 30)
  - Vedder case, 2003-2005 (Box 30)
  - Flower photographs, 1957-1958 (Box 30)
  - 75th birthday party photographs, 1954; 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Photographs and stamps, 1959-1999 (Box 30)
  - Photographs, 1958-1967 (Box 30)
  - Japan photographs, undated; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - "Misc. Family Memorabilia," photographs, undated; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Reception and award photographs, undated (Box 30)
  - Fairfield University commencement photographs, 1967 (Box 30)
  - Photographs, 1958-1959; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2007 (Box 30)
  - "Photography", 1959 (Box 30)
  - Birmingham Festival of Arts correspondence, 1973 (Box 30)
  - Beethoven painting correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Library of Congress correspondence, 1959 (Box 30)
  - Witkin Gallery correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 30)
  - George Eastman House inventory, 2002 (Box 31)
  - Articles, 1944-1988 (Box 31)
  - Joanna Steichen's autopsy, 2010 (Box 31)
  - George Eastman House finding aid, 2002 (Box 31)
  - MoMA correspondence, 1966 (Box 31)
  - Affidavit, 1996 (Box 31)
  - Land appraisal, 1973 (Box 31)
  - Small purchase, 1961-1963 (Box 31)
  - Greenburg purchases, 1998-2006 (Box 31)
  - Copies of paintings, undated (Box 31)
  - Lux Garden interview, 2007 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence with Minister Modert, 2010 (Box 31)
  - "Profile", 2001 (Box 31)
  - "Bird in Space", 1965 (Box 31)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 31)
  - "Family of Children" correspondence, 1977 (Box 31)
  - Knopf book contract, 1996-2002 (Box 31)
  - Met inventory, 1996 (Box 31)
  - MoMA correspondence, 1966-1977 (Box 31)
  - Greenberg consignments, 2000-2002 (Box 32)
  - Estate gift recipients, 1982-1983 (Box 32)
  - Navy correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Philadelphia Museum correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2013 (Box 32)
  - Tuscon CCP correspondence, 1997 (Box 32)
  - National Gallery correspondence, 1997-2007 (Box 32)
  - Greenberg case, 2005 (Box 32)
  - Stamps, 2001-2002 (Box 32)
  - MoMA correspondence, 1993-2007 (Box 32)
  - Luxembourg media, 2012-2013; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Paris exhibit, 2007 (Box 32)
  - "Edward Steichen: Celebrity Design", 2010 (Box 32)
  - "The Family of Man" media, 2013; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - "Steichen's Castle and Tower", undated; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - "NY-LUX", 2014 (Box 32)
  - "Mois Européen de la Photographie", 2013 (Box 32)
  - "distURBANces", 2012 (Box 32)
  - "Paedagogica Historica", 2013 (Box 32)
  - "Du Wassertuerm zu Diddeléng", undated (Box 32)
  - "Edward Steichen Photographe", 2004 (Box 32)
  - "Steichen's Way" I-IX, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" X-XVIII, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" XIX-postscript and edit of XX, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" chronology, 1879-1957, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" chronology, 1958-1973, and bibliography, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" In Extenso II and chronology, 1879-1957, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" chronologym 1958-1973, and bibliography, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" In Extenso I and Millstien articles, undated (Box 33)
  - "Steichen's Way" book plates, undated; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Clippings, 1942-1983 (Box 34)
  - "Carl Sandburg", 1969 (Box 34)
  - "Art in America", 1963; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - "The Fifty Stars of the USA", 1959 (Box 34)
  - "The Bitter Years", 1996 (Box 34)
  - "Art in America", 1961; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - "Vanity Fair", 1960 (Box 34)
  - "Vogue", 1938-1959; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - "Steichen's Legacy", 2000 (Box 34)
  - "Image", 1991 (Box 34)
  - 75th birthday dinner, 1954 (Box 34)
  - "Steichen: A Centennial Tribute", 1979 (Box 34)
  - "Carl Sandburg Farm National Historic Site", 1968 (Box 34)
  - "The Creative Mind and Method", 1960 (Box 34)
  - "Edward Steichen" note cards, 2000 (Box 34)
  - "The Paintings of Edward J. Steichen", 1988 (Box 35)
  - "Edward Steichen", 1993 (Box 35)
  - "Photo-Secession", 1960 (Box 35)
  - "Saturday Review", 1959 (Box 36)
  - "Edward Steichen: The Royal Photographic Society Collection", 1997 (Box 36)
  - "The Family of Man", 1960-1994 (Box 36)
  - "Saturday Review", 1968 (Box 36)
  - "Better Homes and Gardens", 1938 (Box 36)
  - "Cliärrwer Bilderbouch", 1981 (Box 36)
  - "Grand-Duché de Luxembourg exposition de photographies", 1997 (Box 36)
  - "Playbill", 1960 (Box 36)
  - "Photographs", 1999 (Box 36)
  - "Image", 1983 (Box 36)
  - "Infinity", 1954 (Box 36)
  - "Homage à Edward Steichen", 1994 (Box 36)
  - "A House in an Apartment", undated (Box 36)
  - Media, 1967-1969 (Box 36)
  - "Steichen the Photographer", 1961 (Box 36)
  - "Steichen Fotograf", 1968 (Box 36)
  - "The Picture Universe", 1960 (Box 36)
  - "The New York Times Magazine", 1959 (Box 37)
  - "Life", 1955 (Box 37)
  - "Collier's", 1932 (Box 37)
  - "Look", 1963 (Box 37)
  - "Invisible Threads", 1981 (Box 38)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 38)
  - Puerto Rico photographs, 1961 (Box 38)
  - California photographs, undated (Box 38)
  - Umpawaug Christmas slideshow, 1967 (Box 38)
  - "Carl Sandburg Farm National Historic Site", 1968 (Box 38)
  - Sandburg book dummy, 1966 (Box 38)
  - Correspondence with Paus'l, 1904 (Box 38)
  - "References to Eduard J. Steichen in 'Camera Work'", undated (Box 38)
  - R.R. Donnelley and Sons, Co. advertisement, undated (Box 38)
  - Joanna Steichen, Montauk House, photographs, 1998 (Box 38)
  - Joanna Steichen photographs, 1996-2001 (Box 38)
  - Photographs and clippings, 1962-1973 (Box 38)
  - Sandburg photographs, 1967 (Box 38)
  - Albee and Thomas photographs, 1964-1991; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Umpawaug photographs, 1964 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 1962-1963 (Box 38)
  - Luxembourg photographs, undated (Box 38)
  - Sandburg biography, undated (Box 38)
- 25 June 2014 Acquisition, 1894-1975; 5.25; (4 boxes)
  - Letter from Edward Steichen to great aunt May concerning birth of Kate Steichen, undated (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - Small Steichen family photographs, 1894-1896, undated (Box 40)
  - Photographs of Clara, Kate, Mary, and dogs, 1912-1943, undated (Box 40)
  - "Voulangis Pre WWI," photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "Pea Green Boat I," photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "Mary with Andre the Hero," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Nell and Grandfather," photograph, circa 1929 (Box 40)
  - "Carol Silverburg and George Wells," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Umpawaug, First House," photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "Steichen and dog," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Mary," photograph, circa 1930 (Box 40)
  - "Kate and Nell, by Steichen," photograph, circa 1928 (Box 40)
  - "Linda and Nell looking up," photographs, circa 1933 (Box 40)
  - "Clara and Nell," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Mary and Donkey, Voulangis," photograph, 1911- (Box 40)
  - Lady with and without bonnet, photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Baptismal Fountain Dedicated to Nell," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Miscellaneous photographs of Mary Steichen Calderone", undated (Box 40)
  - "Umpawaug on Winter Night," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Kate in Voulangis Garden," photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "Steichen with Smoke Wreath," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Nell (cropped from photo of Nell and Kate)," photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - "Kate at Voulangis," photograph, circa 1926 (Box 40)
  - "Mary and Nell, by Steichen," photograph, circa 1927 (Box 40)
  - "Nell, by Steichen," photograph, circa 1929 (Box 40)
  - "Kate by Nell, by Steichen," photograph, circa 1926 (Box 40)
  - "Edward Steichen Middle Years, By Ed Stein," photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "Childhood Photographs of E.J. Steichen", undated (Box 40)
  - "Miscellaneous Interior Photographs of House", undated; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - "Photographs of Steichen, by Fritz Gruber", undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
  - "The Bitter Years Show at MOMA, Installation Shots," photographs, undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Steichen's house, Voulangis, photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - Steichen's dog, negatives, undated (Box 40)
  - Outdoors, unidentified, negatives, undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Steichen military photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "E.J. Steichen at 18 months, Luxembourg," photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - WWI aerial photographers, photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "Edward Steichen, by Joanna Steichen," photographs, undated; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Edward Steichen and mother, photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - WWI Headquarters-Photo Section, photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - Edward Steichen, 9 years old, photograph, undated (Box 40)
  - Steichen, by various photographers, photographs, 1954, undated (Box 40)
  - Aerial Survey of Redding, Connecticut, photographs, 1934- (Box 40)
  - Trees and icicles, unidentified photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - Steichen, by Otake, photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom, photographs, 1963- (Box 40)
  - Steichen, photographs, circa 1900-1910 (Box 40)
  - Steichen, by unidentified photographer, photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - "Steichen and Studio Assistants," photograph, circa 1932 (Box 40)
  - "My Father and Mother," photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - Unidentified photograph, 1950-12-09 (Box 40)
  - Unidentified photographs, undated (Box 40)
  - Unidentified photograph with letter to Kate on verso, circa 1980 (Box 40)
  - "Nell in Canoe at Umpawaug," photograph, circa 1934 (Box 41)
  - Steichen, by Wayne Miller, photographs, undated; 4 folders (Box 41)
  - Unidentified photographs, undated (Box 42)
  - "Lt. Commander Steichen with Navel Captain (Oliver Jansen?) in Steel Helmets", photograph, 1975- (Box 42)
  - "Nell Blowing Bubbles," photograph, undated (Box 42)
  - "Dana [Steichen], by Dorothea Lange," photograph, 1952- (Box 42)
  - Steichen at award ceremony, photographs, undated (Box 42)
  - Steichen and unidentified man, by Penn, photograph, 1947- (Box 42)
  - Steichen, by Homer Page, photograph, undated (Box 42)
  - Steichen, by Halsman, photograph, undated (Box 42)
  - Steichen, by unidentified photographer, photographs, undated (Box 43)
  - Steichen, by H. Shaw, photograph, undated (Box 43)
  - Steichen, by Peter Fink, photographs, undated (Box 43)
  - "US Navy Photograph, by Edward Steichen", 1943- (Box 43)
  - Steichen, by Arnold Newman, photograph, undated (Box 43)
  - Steichen, by Joan Miller, photograph, undated (Box 43)
  - Unidentified photograph, by Florence Homalka, undated (Box 43)
  - Steichen, by unidentified photographer, photograph, undated (Box 43)